[ Cheering ]
[欢呼声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning and welcome to
&gt;&gt; 早上好  欢迎大家来听
Auto Layout techniques in
界面生成器 (Interface Builder) 中
Interface Builder.
自动布局 (Auto Layout) 新技术
I'm Jonathon Mah.
我是 Jonathon Mah
I'm an engineer on the Interface
我是界面生成器小组的
Builder team, and I'll be joined
工程师  稍后我的同事
onstage shortly by my colleague
Jason Yao 也会上台与大家
Jason Yao.
进行分享
In this session, we'll be
在这个演讲中  我们会
starting with a partly built iOS
从一个半成品的 iOS 应用程序着手
app and use that to demonstrate
用这个半成品给大家展示
a series of layout and
一系列布局和
interaction techniques.
交互技术
Now it seems like every few
好了  最近似乎每隔几个月
months there's a new app to help
就会冒出一款帮人们寻找
people find dates, and this is
约会对象(红枣)的新应用  现在
another one of those months.
正好又赶上这种时候
So this is the app we're
我手上就有这么一款
starting with.
应用
[ Laughter ]
[笑声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Like other dating apps using
使用自动布局  和使用约会(找红枣)软件
Auto Layout is about building
本质上都是要建立关系
between views.
视图间的关系
And building relationships does
而建立关系  着实需要花一番
take work.
功夫
But it's the kind of work that's
但这种事情  恰恰非常值得
rewarding because having laid
下一番功夫  因为一旦我们用
out our interface using
约束条件设置好界面
constraints, our app can scale
我们的应用就能在多种
across a variety of screen sizes
不同尺寸的屏幕上运行
and adaptations, including ones
甚至在未来某种未知尺寸
which might not exist yet.
的屏幕上  都能够完美自适应
Now, if you've never used Auto
如果有人还从没使用过
Layout before, there's some
自动布局  网上有很多
great resources online and past
很好的资源  另外  往期的 WWDC
sessions from WWDCs.
相关演讲  也可以一看
But today we've got a lot of
但鉴于今天我们已经
content to get through, so we're
有很多内容要讲  所以那些
not going to cover the basics.
基本内容  我就省略不说了
In fact, we have six techniques
准确地说  今天我们有六项内容
that we'll be walking through.
需要给大家一一展示
You can use these in your own
这些都可以应用到我们的
apps, either as is or combine
应用中  可以各自独立使用  或者
them together to form a larger
互相结合  做出更复杂的整体
effect.
效果
And with that, let's just jump
以上是概述  下面我们立马
right into the first one, which
开始讲表单中的第一项
is changing layout at runtime.
在运行时改变布局
Now at the top of our app we
我刚刚提到的应用  在界面顶端
have a slider area where the
设置了一个滑动条区域  用户可以
user can set a distance.
在这里设置距离范围
And usually, we expect the user
通常来说  我们的预期是
to set this once and then not
用户会设置一次  之后的一段时间内
need to change it for a while.
都不会再进行调整
So we'd like for this area to be
因此我们就希望  稍后这一区域
able to collapse away and reduce
能够自动收起  这样可以让
clutter in our interface.
界面看起来更清爽
Now, if we think about this from
如果我们从设置布局的角度
a layout perspective, what we're
来考虑这个问题  我们希望
trying to do is collapse the
达到的目标是  把这一区域的
height of this area to 0.
高度收起到零
So, if we add a height
所以我们是不是可以
constraint and then set the
添加一个高度约束  然后设置
constant to 0.
其常量值为零呢
If we did this in Interface
如果我们在界面生成器中
Builder, we'd get something like
这样做  得到的结果差不多是
this.
这样
So what we're seeing here is our
就会像这张图上一样  显示出
layout with a bunch of red lines
我们布局的区域  和一堆红线
indicating that our layout
这意味着我们的布局
doesn't have a solution.
无法实现
We have what's called a
现在这种状况就叫作
conflict.
约束冲突 (conflict)
So a conflict means that we've
约束冲突  就是说我们
asked the layout engine to do
在要求布局引擎执行
multiple incompatible things.
多项互相矛盾的事情
In this case, set the height of
在目前这个例子中  矛盾在于
this area to 0 while also
设置区域高度为零
keeping the height large enough
同时要求该区域保持足够高度
to fit the content inside of it.
以完整容纳区域内部的内容
The technique that we'll use to
我们可以用下面这种技巧
solve this is to take the view
来解决这一问题  我们先要把
that contains our control, our
当前这个包含着控件
slider, and our labels, and
滑动条  和文本标签的视图
we'll wrap it in another view,
包裹在另一个视图里
here indicated in orange.
就是图中用橙色标出的区域
Now instead of just collapsing
现在我们再执行收起
the view containing our
就不是收起包含控件的
controls, we'll collapse this
内部视图  而是收起整个外围
outer view.
视图
The inner view maintains its
而内部视图还保持着
full height and satisfies all
原来的高度  并满足所有
its constraints.
约束条件
But the outer view clips the
但外围视图  会对内部视图
inner view because clips
进行剪裁  因为 clipsToBounds
ToBounds is enabled.
属性设置成了是
And this gets the effect of
通过以上设置  就可以达到
hiding the interface elements.
隐藏某些界面元素的效果
Let's see how this looks in
我们切到 Xcode 看一下具体代码
Xcode.
怎么写
So we have the slider area
在界面生成器里  我们已经
designed in Interface Builder
在这里设计好了这个滑动条
right here, and we're designing
区域  设计时需要
it in the expanded state, so we
在"展开"模式下设计  这种
can work with it more easily.
模式下  我们比较好操作
So since it's expanded in
这个区域在界面生成器里
Interface Builder, we'll be
是展开的  所以我们是在
collapsing it at runtime.
运行时  才执行收起效果
So we'll create a constraint at
因此我们就需要在运行时创建一个
runtime to set this, the outer
约束条件  先把外围视图的
wrapping view height to 0.
高度设置为零
And then, at some point, in
这样在某个时刻  如果用户
response to the user touching
触发了约束按钮  作为约束
the button, we'll activate that
响应  再去激活执行这项
constraint.
约束条件
Now if that were the only thing
但如果约束条件只有这些
we did we'd still hit the
布局还是会出现
conflict situation that we saw
之前所见的约束冲突
before, so we'll deactivate a
所以我们还需要再解除
different constraint, the bottom
另一个约束才行  这里我们
edge of the control container to
解除外围视图控件容器的
the wrapping view.
底端约束
So this will allow the outer
这样我们的外围视图就
view to collapse.
可以顺利收起了
Let's look at the full code for
我们来看一下完整的代码
This is in our view controller
这是我们的视图控制器
subclass and so we have three
子类  这里有三个界面控制器
properties.
属性
Two of them are outlets to both
其中两个  是 Outlet 连接属性
that wrapping view and the lower
分别连接到外围视图  和底端
constraint, and we have a
约束  还有一个属性用来
property to store our 0 height
存储之前设置的  高度归零
constraint.
的约束
In response to touching the
作为触发按钮后的
button, the first thing we'll do
响应  首先需要确认的是
is ensure that the 0 height
如果此前还没有创建高度
constraint is created, if we
归零的约束  触发按钮后
haven't made it already.
先创建这个约束
And then because we want the
又因为我们希望运行效果是
behavior to toggle between shown
在显示和隐藏之间切换
and hidden, we'll figure out
所以还要加一行代码判断
which direction we're going.
是要隐藏  还是要显示
With that done, we'll then
做完这些后  我们再
deactivate and activate the
按需解除和激活那些
constraint that we want to have
我们需要的约束
-- that we want to get our
那些可以实现最终
interface into the final state.
隐藏效果的约束
Now, if you notice carefully,
如果大家观察仔细
we're deactivating one
我们在激活一项
constraint before activating
约束条件前  先解除了
another constraint.
另一项约束
We're not simply toggling both.
而不是简单的二者切换
And the reason for that is that
我们要这样做的原因
Auto Layout tries to help us
是因为自动布局会自动帮助
avoid the conflict situation.
我们避免约束冲突
Because, as soon as we get into
如果我们编程时出现了
a conflict, it'll log a message
约束冲突  自动布局就会自动
to the console saying hey, I've
报告控制中心  说  听着
detected that these constraints
我发现了以下这些约束条件
are conflicting with each other.
相互冲突了
So if we activated, for example,
所以举个例子  如果我们在
0 height while the bottom
底端约束未解除的状况下
constraint was still activated,
激活高度归零约束
we'd get that message.
就会收到约束冲突警报
By deactivating first, we avoid
先解除一个约束  就可以避免
that.
报错
So this is what we need to get
好了  做完这些就可以让我们的
our interface in the final
界面达到最终的
state, but we also would like to
隐藏效果  但我们还希望能够
animate the results so that the
动画显示隐藏过程  这样
user can see -- maintain some
用户能看到  界面在展开
context in the application as
和收起之间  能有一个过渡
the transition happens.
前后不会显得太突兀
So to do that we'll use a UIView
要实现动态转变  我们还要加一个
animation block, and we'll wrap
UIView 动画块  然后再在动画中调用
a call to layout if needed.
layoutIfNeeded 立即实现布局
So this evaluates the
这一步会自动
constraints, gets frame values
评估约束条件  获取外框数值  并自动
and applies to them to a view,
应用到视图上
and then UIView animation will
然后 UIView 动画会抓取这些
capture that and animate the
动画参数  为你实现动画效果
So we're deactivating the bottom
前面说了  解除底端
constraint and that gives us
约束  就可以实现
this animation effect.
这种动画效果
This isn't quite the effect that
这和我心中想要的效果还
I want, but I can change that
不太一样  但如果想更改效果
simply by keeping the code
绝大部分的代码我都
exactly the same and changing
不需要改动  只需要调整
which constraint our edge
边缘约束所关联的约束条件
constraint outlet is connected
是关联到容器顶端  还是底端
If I had said connected to the
如果我预先设置为
top constraint, then the
关联到顶端约束  那么
animation changes and it gets
动画效果就会产生相应改变
the effect that actually I think
变成这样  其实我更喜欢这种效果
So we just saw an example of
我们刚刚看到的例子  演示了
changing the layout in our app
如何通过改变约束
by changing the constraints.
来改变界面的布局
Now let's look at another way to
下面我们再看看另一种
change the layout, and we'll use
改变布局的方法  我们将用这种方法
that to track touch.
来跟踪触控点
So we have this central card
在我们的应用中  有这样
area in our app, and we'd like
一个中央卡片区域  我们现在
it to follow a touch around the
希望这个卡片区域能够跟随
screen and add a little rotation
触控点在屏幕上移动  并在移动
as you get close to the edge and
到接近屏幕边缘时  稍作旋转
snap back once you let it go.
同时松手后能自动复位
So the view's position onscreen
一个视图在屏幕上的位置
is generally defined by its
一般是由外框 (frame) 属性
frame and when we're using
来定义的  而当我们
constraints and have constraints
使用约束时  当我们对这个视图
to this view, the layout engine
使用约束时  frame 属性具体
owns the value of this frame.
的数值在布局引擎里
So the value itself is computed
也就是说  具体数值是引擎
from the constraints.
由约束条件计算得出的
But there's another property
但除此之外  还有另一个属性
that affects the view's position
会影响视图在屏幕上
onscreen and that is the
所处的位置  那就是
transform, and this applies an
transform  这个属性会对
offset from the frame.
外框施加形变
So the type of this is a
我们要说的类型  叫作
CGAffineTransform.
仿射变换 (CGAffineTransform)
And this lets us add a
通过这个属性  我们可以
translation, a rotation, and a
在引擎通过约束计算完
scale that gets applied after
外框位置和大小后  再对外框
the frame has been computed from
进行平移  旋转  和
constraints.
缩放
So we can use this to get the
我们按上述所说的方法实施
effect that we're after, and
就可以得到想要的效果
I'll jump over to a demo and
我现在就直接切换到示例
show you how it's done.
给大家演示一下
Okay. So here is our app in
好了  这就是我们应用程序的
Interface Builder.
界面生成器
And we'd like to make the
现在我们想要让
central card area move around
中央卡片区域随着屏幕触控
with the touch.
四处移动
Now I've just added a gesture
我刚刚已经从对象库里
recognizer, a pan gesture
往这个区域里添加了一个
recognizer, from the object
手势识别器  一个
library to this area.
拖动手势识别器 (pan gesture recognizer)
And when I add a gesture
我添加过手势识别器之后
recognizer, it appears at the
它就会显示在
top level of the scene, so
场景的顶层  这里我们可以在
[inaudible] and in the outline
场景存放区和提纲视图里看到
view.
我现在打开辅助编辑器
so we can see our view
这样我们就可以看到
controller code.
视图控制器的代码
And I'll control drag from that
然后我按住控制键  把拖动手势
pan gesture recognizer to a spot
识别器拖拽到我们源代码
in our source code.
的这个地方
And this will let me add an
这样就可以添加一个
outlet.
outlet 连接
Or, in this case, I want to
或者像现在这种情况
connect an action, and I'll call
连接一个动作  我起名叫
it panCard.
panCard (卡片拖动)
I'll switch the type from any to
然后再把类型  从"任何"
pan gesture recognizer.
改为拖动手势识别器
This is the type of the
这就是这项参数的
parameter.
类型
And specifying pan gesture
指定拖动手势识别器
recognizer let's me use
就让我可以
properties of that gesture
在动作方法内使用
recognizer within the action
手势识别器的属性
All right.
好了
So we have our method stub here.
这里可以看到一个写了半截的方法
And I also have an outlet that's
这里还有一个 outlet 连接
connected to that card view,
连接到卡片视图上
which is what we want to move.
我们要移动的就是这个卡片视图
So, in this method, I'm first
现在  在这个方法里  我首先
going to ask the sender, which
要询问发送者  也就是
is the gesture recognizer, for
手势识别器  请求它的
its translation.
解译结果
In effect, how far the user has
也就是用户到底拖动  或者
panned or dragged.
拖拽了多远
And then I'm going to use the
然后我会用这个解译结果
result to apply a transform to
对当前这个卡片视图
this card view.
施加形变
Now the transform's computed by
具体形变是由这里这个
this helper method right here,
辅助方法计算得出的
which generates both a
这个辅助方法不仅
translation and adds a little
会生成解译结果  还会
rotation, depending on the
根据卡片所在位置  添加
exposition of the card.
一定程度的旋转效果
So I'm going to hit build and
现在我们就按下编译并运行
run, and we'll see how this
试试  看运行出来结果如何
All right.
好了
And so we have our app.
这就是应用界面了
And now, if I touch and move, we
现在  如果我按住屏幕移动
get a rotation, and it will
可以看到旋转效果  卡片还会
follow the touch.
跟随触控点移动
And then if I let go, now the
但如果我现在松手  目前
card just stays where it is,
卡片只会停在原地不动
because we're never resetting
因为我们代码中还没有重置
the transform.
形变
It's just staying the last value
形变量还停留在最后一次
that we gave it.
设置的值上
If I touch and move again, we'll
如果我再触控移动一下
see that it will snap back to
会看到此时卡片才会自动
the original position.
复位到初始位置
That's because the transform
这是因为形变不是随之
isn't offset from that.
偏移的
So, as soon as we go back with a
所以一旦我们再一次提交
new translation, we're going to
新的解译结果  就总会
be relative to the original
和初始 frame 属性值
frame.
相关
So we'd like the card to return
我们现在希望卡片能在
back to the center once we're
拖拽移动过后  自动复位到屏幕
done with it.
中央
Once we let go of the touch.
只要松手就自动复位
Now we can do that by looking at
要实现这一点  我们可以先看一下
the state of the gesture
手势识别器的状态
recognizer.
属性
So we have the same code here.
这里的代码是一样的
And then, when the state is
然后等这个形变状态完结后
ended, we'll reset the transform
我们就重置 transform 属性
back to the identity transform.
设置该值为 identity  还原到最初状态
Let's build and run again.
我们再编译并运行一下
So now when we release the card
现在我们移动后松手  卡片就会
snaps back.
自动复位
So, of course, we'd like to
当然了  我们还希望
animate that snapping back, so
给这个复位过程加一些动画效果
let's just do that.
这就加一下
So we have the same reset to
这里的代码还保留着重置到
identity code.
identity 最初状态
And I'm using the UIView animate
然后我们加一个带 spring (震动)
variant with the spring options.
可选效果的 UIView 动画
So this will give us a different
加了动画后的效果又不太一样了
So I'll build and run again.
再编译并运行一下
So now, if I release the card,
现在我再松开卡片
it will bounce back to the
可以看到  卡片会弹回
original position, and I kind of
初始位置  我还挺喜欢
like this playful behavior.
这种活泼的显示效果的
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thanks. Yeah, I think people are
谢谢大家  我觉得会有人
going to show their friends
会给朋友们展示这点的
this.
我觉得这样挺好
All right.
好了
So we just saw that the view
我们刚刚讲了  视图
position is a combination of
在屏幕上的位置和很多项
multiple properties.
属性相关
Not only the frame, which is
不光取决于由约束计算
derived from the constraints,
得出的外框 (frame)
but we can also use the
我们还可以通过使用
transform to affect where the
变形 (transform) 来控制视图
view is onscreen.
在屏幕上的位置
And that was just a couple lines
要实现这种有趣的效果
of code to add this fun
我们只需要添加寥寥几行
interaction.
代码
So I hope that you guys will
所以我衷心希望大家能够
play around with that in your
在你们的应用里尝试一下
own apps, because it's a lot of
这个功能  因为真的很好玩儿
fun.
对于临时的视图改变
temporary changes, like we saw.
形变非常好用  像我们刚看的
Like tracking a touch or an
比如用来跟踪触控点
animation between states in your
或是为界面的两个状态之间添加动画
interface.
效果
And then we reset back to the
但要记得在形变之后重置
identity transform when we're
还原到最初的 identity 状态
So now that we have our app
好了  现在我们的应用界面有了
acting playfully, let's talk
活泼有趣的效果  我们再来
about making the text look
谈谈怎么让文字显示更加完美
To do that, we'll support
为了做到这点  我们需要支持
dynamic type.
动态字体 (Dynamic Type)
Dynamic type is a technology on
动态字体是 iOS 自带的一项技术
iOS that provides both a set of
这项技术  既给开发者提供了一套
text styles.
文字样式
For example, headline, body,
比如有标题  正文
caption.
和说明
And user control over the size
还可以让用户控制这些样式中
of those styles.
的字体大小
Here's a few example apps, and
这是一些在应用程序中的举例  这些程序中
this is with a default text size
用的都是默认文字样式的字号
Now, if the user preferred a
现在  如果用户希望调整到
larger text size, for example,
比方说  更大的显示字号
we'd see messages adjust.
短信中的文字就会做相应调整
So the text increases, and then
可以看到文字变大了  然后文字
all the graphic around -- the
周围的所有图像  比如
bubbles around the messages
包住短信的文字气泡  都会相应
increase.
变大
Also the input field gets
同时  输入框也会相应变大
Similarly, with calendar, an
同样的  在日历应用中的
event layer.
事件层
And our app looks like this.
我们的 app 看起来是这样的
Yeah, nothing changed.
和短信息中的改变一样
Or, depending on how we created
或者  根据不同的程序设计
our app, it might look like
增大字号后  也可能变成
this.
这样
Where some text increases but
一部分文字的字号变大了
our layout is not right, and its
但整体布局不对  导致文字
unreadable.
不可读
Fortunately, Interface Builder
好在通过界面生成器
makes it easy to fix this up for
我们可以轻而易举地修复这个问题
us.
我们现在就看一下  如何
do that right now.
进行改进
All right.
好了
Back to our app, and let's take
回到我们的应用程序  我们看一下
a look at making these two
怎样修改这两个
labels respect the system font
文本标签  好让它们能沿用系统字号
size.
现在  我先选中下方的
lower label here.
这个文字标签
And over in the inspector, I'll
然后在审查器中  找到
check the automatically adjust
"自动调整字体"的复选框
font checkbox.
并勾选
Now, if you've got a keen eye,
如果大家观察足够仔细
you'll notice as soon as I did
会发现我一旦勾选这一项
that, I had this little warning
这里就弹出了一个警报
icon pop up.
图标
And this reminds us that for
这个警报是为了提醒我们
this property to take effect, we
如果要应用这项属性  我们
need to specify a text style for
首先得为这个文本标签规定好
the label.
文字样式
So right now the font for this
当前这个文本标签的字号
label is a fixed value of system
是固定的值  设置在系统12号 (System 12)
And I'll change it to a text
我现在就把它改成
style by opening the inspector
一种文字样式  只需打开审查器
and selecting an appropriate
然后选择一个合适的
style.
样式
In this case, I'll choose
在这里  我们选用
caption one.
说明一 (Caption 1)
So this happened to correspond
这个样式刚好和默认文字样式中
to system 12 at the default text
的系统 12 号一模一样
style, so our canvas looks the
所以目前画布上还没有任何变化
I'll do the same with the upper
现在我把上方的这个文本标签也
label.
改一下
This already had a text style
这个标签已经设好了文本样式
And I'll build and run again.
编译并运行一下
Okay. So this comes up and it
好了  现在这个界面显示出来
looks the same because we
和之前没什么两样  因为
haven't changed the text size
我们还没有改变字号大小
Now we can change the text size
要改变字号大小
by using the settings app on the
可以通过模拟器里的"系统设置"
simulator, but it's a little
应用程序  但那就要在
cumbersome to switch back and
我们的应用和系统设置应用
forth between settings and our
两个应用间不断切换  有点麻烦
app.
所以我想给大家演示一下
way to do that.
另一种方法
If I jump back to Xcode, I can
如果我切换回 Xcode  可以在
use the application menu to open
应用菜单中打开  开发者工具
develop a tool accessibility
然后进入  辅助功能审查器
So, from here, I can choose to
打开这个窗口后  可以把
target the simulator.
目标一项设为模拟器
And on the settings tab I get
然后点击设置标签页  下方就
this font size slider.
会出现一个字号滑动条
So I'll pull up the simulator
现在我调出模拟器
side by side, and now I can
两个窗口左右放在一起  就可以
change this slider and see our
通过滑动这个字号滑动条  在屏幕上
app react in real time.
实时看到字号变化
This makes it a lot easier to
这样来测试对动态字体
test dynamic type changes.
的改变  就简单多了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
By the way, if I had an iPhone
顺便说一句  如果我同时还
plugged in or set up for
插着 iPhone  或有 iPhone
development here, I can also
设置好了开发模式  我也可以把
choose to target that connected
目标设置为连接上的这些 iPhone
So we see our app adjusting --
这里我们可以看到  应用在调整
reacting to the font size, but
在根据字号变化  实时调整
if it gets too large then our
但当字号过大时
labels are running into each
这两个文本标签就会撞到一起
other and overlapping.
相互重叠
So let's go fix that.
让我们再调整一下这部分
So, in Interface Builder,
在界面生成器里
whoops, I'm going to jump back
糟糕  我先切换回来
I want to get that out the way.
把这个窗口挪到一边
The text area, down here, the
下面这里  这个文本区域
size of that is defined by a
定义这个区域的大小的是一个
fixed height constraint
固定数值的高度约束
[inaudible] constant over here.
在这里可以看到  是一个常量值
Now, instead, we'd like this
现在我们希望这一区域的
size to vary depending on the
大小  能根据内部所需要显示的
size of the labels within it.
文本标签大小  自行调整
So we have the bottom label
我们已经把下方的文本标签
constrained to the bottom and
通过约束绑定到区域底端
the top constrained to the top.
把上方的标签  约束到顶端
So, if we added a vertical
现在我们只需要在这两者之间
constraint between the two,
添加一个垂直约束
there'd be enough information to
这样一来  文本标签的
size this area from the
字号大小和几条相关约束中所
constraints of the labels and
包含的信息  就足够程序自动计算出
the size of the labels
这个文本区域该有
themselves.
多大
So let's do that.
让我们实践一下
I'll control drag from label to
按住控制键把一个文本标签拖到另一个
another.
上面
And I can choose to add a
这里  我可以选择添加
vertical spacing constraint, so
一个垂直间距约束
this will keep the labels
这就可以保证两个文本标签的
separated by the same distance
垂直间距一直维持着
they are in the canvas right
当前二者在画布上的
now.
距离
I can choose to add a vertical
我也可以选择添加一个
baseline standard spacing.
文本基线垂直标准间距
So this is similar to vertical
这和垂直间距差不多
spacing except UIKit will adjust
唯一不同的地方是  UIKit 会根据
the constant of this constraint,
这个约束所涉及的多个文本
depending on the text style and
标签的具体文字样式和
the current font sizes of the
当前字号自动调整
labels involved.
约束的常量值
So I'll choose to add one of
我们现在就添加这个约束吧
And now I can select and remove
现在我就可以选中并删除
the fixed type constraint and
原先的固定数值的高度约束
then build and run again.
再编译并运行
So now things are looking a lot
现在这个界面看起来就舒服
better.
多了
Our content area is adjusting
下方的内容区域会跟着
for larger sizes and also
文字字号变大自动调大
shrinking down for smaller
也可以跟着字号变小而
sizes, if people want larger
缩小  喜欢在界面上
information density on their
看到更浓缩内容的人可以试试
So, using two properties in the
总结一下  通过应用文本标签审查器
label inspector, both the font
里的两项属性  也就是字体属性
and the dynamic type property,
和动态字体属性
we can make our labels adjust
我们可以让文本标签根据
dynamically as the font size
字号大小改变而进行自动
changes.
调整
And we saw using accessibility
我们还看了怎样通过辅助功能审查器
inspector to test different
来测试不同字号大小的显示效果
There's a talk later this
稍后  在今日下午
afternoon, Building Apps With
还有一场演讲  叫《Building Apps With
Dynamic Type, with a lot more
Dynamic Type》  那场演讲
information, and after this
有更多相关信息  今天的
session, if you want to try out
演讲之后  如果你想知道
how your own apps looks, if you
改变字号大小后  你们的应用
change the font size, you can
看起来是什么样子
also get to the setting directly
也可以直接在手机端的设置里
on your phone.
直接调整
If you go through accessibility,
如果大家进入辅助功能设置
you get the larger accessibility
可以看到辅助设置里有
sizes' option, which gives a
大字体选项  为显示字体
large range of values for the
提供了很大范围的
type to vary on.
可选字号值
So check that out.
大家可以去试试
Now it's time to add some more
接下来  我们就该介绍如何
views to our app.
为应用程序添加更多的视图了
And I'd like to bring up Jason
下面就有请 Jason 上台
to introduce you to this safe
来为大家介绍安全区域 (Safe Area)
Jason.
掌声欢迎 Jason
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name's Jason Yao.
我的名字是 Jason Yao
I'm an Interface Builder
是一位界面生成器
engineer, and it's a pleasure to
工程师  很高兴今天
be with you here today.
能在此和大家进行分享
We're going to continue on with
我会继续用这个约会(找红枣)应用
our dating app journey and talk
作为模版和例子  再给大家
about three more techniques.
讲解剩下的三项技术
And so, the first thing I want
好了  首先的一点
to talk to you about is what do
假设我们在一个视图控制器里
you do when you got a view
上方设置了顶部导航栏
controller and you've got a
下方设置了底部
navigation bar and a tab bar and
标签导航栏  而我们现在想
you want to make sure your views
确保中间的视图内容不要被
are positioned so that they're
这上下两个导航栏遮挡
not covered up by those bars?
这种情况下  该怎样定位中间的视图
As you may have heard, there's a
可能大家已经听说过了
new layout guide on iOS 11
在 iOS 11 里  新推出了一个布局指南
called the Safe Area Layout
叫作安全区域 (Safe Area) 布局指南
Guide.
这是 UIView 的一个新属性
It works with Auto Layout and
在自动布局里也可以用
what it is is a rectangle that
实质上  就是一个长方形区域
is around the bars and container
一个被两个导航栏  和容器边界
edges and then you can constrain
框起来的区域  我们可以在此区域内
your views as you expect.
按需求对视图进行约束
If you had to do this thing in
如果以前你就有过这种布局需求
the past, you may remember the
你可能还记得当时需要
Top and Bottom Layer Guide on
通过 UIViewController 里的
UIViewController.
顶底端 (Top and Bottom) 布局指南设置
Those are deprecated in favor of
在新版的安全区域设置方法下  这两项
this new safe area.
都废止不用了
The Safe Area Layout Guide is
安全区域布局指南会更加
easier to use.
便捷好使
It's more expressive and allows
效果更多样  还可以实现
you to do a few new things, like
一些前所未有的新效果  比如
be able to center vertically
可以在顶底端导航栏的
between your bars.
中间区域进行居中
And that way as the [inaudible]
使用这个效果之后  如果屏幕方向改变
and the size of your height
或者  大小或高度改变
changes, say if you rotate in
比如  如果我们旋转到
landscape, your layout will
横屏  我们的布局也会
adjust accordingly.
自动调整
The Safe Area Layout Guide is
安全区域布局指南
also something that can apply to
也可以应用到 tvOS 上
When you target your app and
当我们为 tvOS 设计应用程序
your content for tvOS, you're
设计内容的时候  我们会
going to want to fill the big
希望让设计好的内容铺满整个
screen.
大屏幕
The thing you have to consider
这时我们需要考虑的一点
is that you're going to be on a
就是我们设计的布局  可能会被
wide variety of displays from
显示在很多大小不一的显示屏上
small ones to big ones, flat
屏幕尺寸可能很小  也可能很大
screens to projectors, and you
格式从平板  到投影仪  我们还
need to worry, in video terms,
需要考虑  用视频术语说的话
of something called the overscan
一个叫"过扫描区域"的东西
On some displays, my title here
在一些显示屏上  我这里设计的
can be cut off because it's too
标题  就可能会因离顶部太近而
close to the top.
被切出屏幕
And so you want to adjust your
因此我们就需要适当调整内容布局
content so that it's within the
让它们都包含在安全区域
safe area.
内部
And the Safe Area Layout Guide
然后安全区域布局指南
is going to represent this
就会在 iOS 11 中正确地表达
region in iOS 11 for your tvOS
这部分内容  然后在 tvOS 故事板中
storyboards.
正确显示
Just constrain your views to the
我们只需把视图约束在
content and set it into the safe
内容范围内  包在安全区域内
area and then fill the rest of
然后把剩下的视图用一张
your view with the beautiful
漂亮的背景图片填满
background imagery for your
再展示给用户就好了
It's really easy to enable Safe
要在 iOS 11 和界面生成器中
Area Layout Guide in iOS 11 and
启用安全区域布局指南也
Interface Builder.
非常简单
You can go into your storyboard,
我们只需进入故事板
go to the file inspector, find
点击文件审查器  找到
that box that says use Safe Area
使用安全区域布局指南的
Layout Guides and check it.
复选框  并勾选即可
What's going to happen is that
勾选之后就能看到
the top level view of each of
在我们每一个场景的顶层
your scenes is going to have the
都会出现一个新生成的
new Safe Area Layout Guide, and
安全区域布局指南  然后
then you constrain to it just
就可以用这个来设置约束条件
like you would to other things
和用画布上其他东西设置约束的
inside the canvas.
方法一样
The Safe Area Layout Guide is a
所以  一  安全区域布局指南是
new property on UIView for
UIView 的一个新属性
keeping your content unobscured
二  它可以帮我们确保内容不受遮挡
and title safe, and, if you use
而完整显示  三  如果我们
it on iOS 11 with -- for iOS
在 iOS 11 故事板中
storyboards, will automatically
使用这项属性  只需勾选上
upgrade your constraints for you
复选框  系统就会自动
when you check that box.
帮我们升级所有相关约束条件
Thank you [applause] and that is
谢谢大家  [掌声]  能自动升级
because the geometry between the
也是因为旧的顶底端布局指南
old Top and Bottom Layout Guides
的几何架构  刚好和
will match the new Safe Area
新的安全区域布局指南相
Layout Guide.
匹配
And best of all, that also means
而最棒的一点是  这也意味着
when you use Safe Area Layout
当我们在 Xcode 9 的 iOS 故事板里
Guides on storyboards in Xcode 9
使用安全区域布局指南时
we'll make it sure it's
我们也会确保
backwards deployable to previous
你的代码在所有旧版 iOS 上也可以运行
iOSs.
iOS
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Now I want to talk about a
下面我想跟大家讲的
layout technique for being able
这个布局方法  可以帮助大家
to position yourself relative to
根据父视图来布局我们的
your superview.
视图
This is called proportional
这个方法就叫  按比例
positioning.
定位
And the idea is say if I have a
大致意思是  比如我们应用界面上
dates' card in my dating app and
有这么一张约会对象(红枣)卡片  然后
I want to be able to position it
我现在希望能把这张图片布置在
about 70% down from the
父视图从上往下大约 70% 的
superview.
地方
How do I do this?
该怎么实现这个效果
There are a few techniques
有好几种方法可供我们
available.
选用
The one I want to show you today
但我今天想跟大家演示的
is the idea of using a spacer
是如何使用占位分隔视图 (Spacer View)
Dragging out a view, just a
首先拖拽出一个视图
normal UIView from the object
对象库里随便一个普通的 UIView
Constraining it but not
对这个视图设置约束  但不进行
rendering it.
渲染
And allowing it to be the
就可以用这个占位视图为框架
scaffolding for positioning your
把你想成比例定位的视图  布置到
view in place.
正确的位置
And this technique also applies
这个方法同样可以应用到
to other type of layouts that
其他布局类型中
are used in proportion.
只要成比布局就行
Here's another example, where
这里是另一个例子
I've got a landscape view, with
这是一个横屏的状态
a 1/5, 2/5, and 2/5 proportion.
按 1/5  2/5  和 2/5 的比例分割
And then they're centered along
三个视图按照上述比例  分别
those proportions.
居中显示
So let's go ahead and take a
我们现在就来看一下
look at how to do this inside of
如何在界面生成器里面
Interface Builder.
实现这些
So I've got a basic layout
这里已经有一个
already here.
基础布局了
And, in this case here, I want
在这个例子里  我想要定位
to be able to position my date
布置的  是这张约会对象(红枣)卡片
And it's being pushed in by a
这个视图是由模态视图
form sheet with the modal segue.
里以表单格式推入的
So we're going to zoom in a
我们现在把这里
little closer over here, and
放大一点  这里
I've got two elements that
已经有两个元素
already have some initial
设置好了一些初始
constraints.
约束
I've got a label and I've got an
其中有一个文本标签  和一张
image.
图片
And if we select them both, if
我们把两项都选中  然后
you look really carefully,
如果仔细看
you'll notice that it's blue on
就会发现  两者的左右
the left and right edges but the
边框都是蓝色的  但是
top and bottom are red.
上下边框却是红色的
That means there's some work
这就意味着还有一些东西
that we need to do.
需要我们进一步调试
Whenever you see red in the
在界面生成器的画布上
Interface Builder canvas, it can
只要我们看到红色  就有可能
be one or two things.
是以下两种问题
Either you have too few
要么是我们设置的
constraints and you're
约束不够多  造成了
ambiguous, or you have too many
意义含糊  或者也可能是我们设置了
conflicting.
约束冲突
I just set this up so I know I
我刚设置好这个视图  所以
haven't positioned myself
我知道我还没有把这些元素
vertically in the superview.
关联约束到父视图上
So let's go ahead and do that.
我们现在就设置一下
And we'll do it by creating the
就用占位分隔视图
spacer view.
来设置
So I'm going to type UIView in
现在我在对象库里
the object library.
打一下 UIView
Just drag out the view and
把视图拖拽到想要布置的位置
We'll give it just roughly the
我们大致调整一下
place that I want to see it in
调成它在画布上差不多该
the canvas.
显示的样子
Next, let's do a few setup
接下来  做一些设置工作
First I'm going to mark it as
首先我要把这个视图标记为隐藏
hidden.
设置后  这个视图会在
layout in runtime but we don't
运行时参与布局  但我们并不需要
want [inaudible] and that way
它参与绘制  这样就不用
you don't incur the cost of
浪费资源去绘制这个定位用视图
The other thing I want to do to
要做的另一件事
recognize it is, in the object
就是在对象库里
library, rename it to spacer
把它重命名为占位
70%.
70%
Now we need to add constraints.
现在我们需要添加约束
So I'm going to click on the pin
我们点击固定菜单 (Pin Menu)
We're going to add a top
给它加一个顶端
constraint, a leading
约束  一个左侧约束
constraint, and then maybe give
然后也可以再指定一个
it a width so I can do
宽度吧  这样之后
constraint connections to it.
还可以连接其他约束
Add that. And you can see that
添加上去之后  可以看到
it's already moved horizontally.
这个占位视图横向移动了
But we still have the top and
但可以看到  视图的
bottom edges that are still red,
上下边缘线还是红色的
and that's because we haven't
那是因为我们还没有
specified a height yet.
给它规定高度
We want to make this proportion
我们希望让这个视图的高度
of the superview, so let's go
与父视图成比例  那么现在
ahead and do that.
就去设置一下
I'm going to add a equal height
我来添加一个等高约束
constraint by dragging out from
按住占位分隔视图  向外拖动
the spacer to the superview and
拖到父视图上  在弹出框里
choosing equal heights.
选择等高约束
Now it's using equal heights to
现在占位视图和我的父视图
my superview, but I realize I've
高度相同了  但我发现
got a navigation bar up there.
这个界面上方还有一个导航栏
And I actually wanted equal
所以其实我想要的是
heights to -- well, actually,
高度和...其实是要…哦对了
let's go ahead and set the
我们可以先去设置一下
proportion.
比例
And the thing is I'm still
设好之后  问题是我这个
relative to my superview, and I
的比例  还是和父视图相关的
want to be relative to my safe
但我其实是希望  和安全区域相关
area.
一般来说  我们要调整这个
rebuild the constraint to do
还需要重新编写一下约束
this.
但我想给大家看个新方法
new.
如果我们去到属性
inspector, which is a really
审查器  这个审查器
powerful thing, and you click on
很好使  然后点击
the item, we list now the
项目 (Item)  这里现在会
neighbors that you can retarget
给大家列出可以接收关联约束的
your constraint items --
相邻项目
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And so if I hit safe area, you
所以如果我点击安全区域
can see it's now 70% to my safe
视图高度就变成了安全区域高度的70%
Now let's go ahead and align our
好了  现在我们再去对齐一下
content.
内容
And so I'm going to take my
我们现在把这个
dates' label, drag it over --
"约会对象(红枣)"的文本标签  拖拽到
create a connection using
按住控制键拖拽  创建
control drag and align it to the
一个连接  和占位视图的底端
bottom.
对齐
Now I wanted [inaudible] nicely
我还希望文字能整齐地
along the baseline and so again,
布局在基线上  所以这里
all I need to do is click on the
我们只需再点击一下
constraint I just added.
刚刚添加的约束
Go to the attributes inspector.
再去属性审查器里
And go ahead and set this to the
然后直接在这里改一下
other attribute.
属性就可以了
The really neat thing about Auto
这也是自动布局特别好用的
Layout is you don't have to do
地方之一  我们不一定
just bottom to bottom.
非要底端与底端对齐
You can do something like bottom
我们还可以底端和顶端
to top.
对齐
Or, in this case, since I have a
或者这我们这个例子里
single line label, I'll do
鉴于我只有一行文本标签
bottom to first baseline and
就可以设底端与第一基线对齐
that way, now we're 70% sitting
这样  就正好布置在父视图70%高度
right along the baseline.
并以基线对齐
Let's test it out in a few
我们在不同配置环境下
configurations.
测试一下
So iPhone seven plus portrait
比如 iPhone 7+ 竖屏
using the device bar.
在设备栏可选
And let's take a look in
再试试横屏
landscape and we're 70% there.
也还是在 70% 的位置
And so this is what I want.
正是我想要的效果
So when you need to do this
所以如果我们需要
proportional technique in
在界面生成器里
Interface Builder, use spacer
实现按比例定位  请用占位
views to be able to get you
分隔视图  来帮助我们定位
And you be sure to mark those
不要忘了把这些占位视图
views as hidden so that they're
标记为隐藏  这样它们
not [inaudible] rendering but
才可以不参与渲染
are assisting you at layout to
但依然可以在布局时帮助我们
be able to position your
定位其他页面内容
And if you're doing your layout
如果有人是用编程方式
programmatically, the thing you
设置布局  可以去用一个叫作
can use is the UILayout Guide.
UILayoutGuide (UI布局指南)的东西
And so programmatically, you can
在编程方式里  可以把
use this as the equivalent to
这个布局指南当作占位视图
the spacer views.
来使用
Next. Let's go ahead and talk
下一项  我要给大家介绍
about another type of view that
另一种我们可能会使用
we want to layout.
的布局方法
In this case, we're going to
我们继续以
show you an example of adaptive
约会(找红枣)软件为例子
layout in our dating app, where
给大家演示一个自适应布局
we've got this view of a 4 x 4
这里在竖屏状态下是四乘四的
grid giving me a selection, and
网格  可供用户选择
then it's got a label at the
文本标签设置在上述网格
bottom.
下方
But when I rotate my phone, it's
而当我旋转手机之后
actually going to give me
显示界面会变得
something a little different.
不太一样
It's still going to give me the
还是会以四乘四网格显示出
4 x 4 grid of my dates, but it's
约会对象(红枣)  但在
going to have a text view over
右侧还会有一个文本视图
on the right.
区域
So let's go ahead and see how we
好了  现在让我们看一下如何在
could do adaptive layout using
界面生成器里  用堆栈视图
stack views in Interface
实现自适应布局
Okay. So I've got my dates
好了  这就是我的
storyboard over here and pretty
约会对象(红枣)故事板
much I've got this grid with an
这个网格的初始布局已经
initial layout set up.
差不多设置好了
I'm going to go ahead and first
现在我要做的第一件事
expand the object outline.
是先展开对象大纲
I can hold down option and kind
按住 Option 就可以
of expand everything all at
快速展开所有对象
And [inaudible] give you a tour
我先给大家简单介绍一下
of the setup.
已经设置好了什么
We have a vertical stack view
我们这里是一个垂直堆栈视图
and it's tied with four
用四条约束
constraints to the superview.
绑定到了父视图上
And then it's got three rows,
内容基本上  由三行内容
essentially.
构成
The first row is a nested
第一行是一个
horizontal stack view of the two
两张图片的嵌套水平堆栈
images.
视图
Second row is also a nested
第二行也是一个
stack view of the two images.
两张图片的嵌套堆栈视图
And then the third row is a
之后的第三行  是一个
label.
文本标签
Now you can see that
我们可以看到
everything's kind of equally
所有内容都是
sized and that is because stack
差不多相同大小  那是因为
view has these great properties
堆栈视图有一些很棒的属性
like alignment, distribution,
比如对齐方式  子视图分布
and spacing.
和子视图间距
And there are a lot of options
还有很多可选项
for being able to configure your
可以用于在堆栈视图和
layout using stack views and
嵌套堆栈视图中配置
nests of stack views.
我们的布局
The great part about stack view
堆栈视图的优点
is that it manages your
在于它可以帮我们
constraints for you so there are
管理我们的约束条件
very few constraints that you
所以我们需要手动添加的约束
have to add.
非常少
If you want to find out more
如果有人想更详细地
about the other, distribution
了解子视图分布
and alignments options, be sure
和对齐方式里的其他可选项
to check out the documentation.
请务必去阅读说明文件
Right now we're using fill
现在我们的子视图间距
equally to make sure
设在沿垂直轴线平分
everything's properly sized.
来确保所有内容的尺寸都是合适的
And let's go ahead and tune this
我们现在具体调整一下设置
closer to what I want.
让布局更接近我想要的效果
Okay. So let's first adjust for
首先我们需要调整子视图间距
So I'm going to select all
我现在选中全部
[inaudible] command and select
按住 cmd 键并选中
all my stack views.
全部堆栈视图
And then we're going to give it
然后在属性审查器里
a slightly larger spacing here
把子视图间距属性的数值
in the attribute inspector.
稍微调大一点
I'll set it to maybe 30.
设置到 30 看看
That's a little too big.
有点太大了
So a new to Xcode 9 and iOS 11,
在 Xcode 9 和 iOS 11 里有个新功能
we have a standard spacing
新添了一个选项叫
option that allows the system to
标准间距  可以让系统自动帮你
choose for you.
选择间距
I'm going to use that.
我就用这个了
Now, if you remember back to
希望大家还记得刚刚
Jonathon's talk about dynamic
Jonathon 讲的动态
type, be sure to check out
字体  对于使用了
standard spacing for vertical
文字样式的内容  请大家
stack views using content that's
一定去看一下垂直堆栈视图的
using text styles and checking
标准间距  然后勾选上
this baseline relative.
基线相关
You'll get the same effect of
那样会得到和动态字体一样的
dynamic type that you just saw.
效果  和之前演示的一样
For us, since we have images and
我们现在既有图片又有
labels, we're going to go ahead
文本标签  所以就留着
and just leave it unchecked.
不勾选这一项了
And the next thing I want to do
下一项我希望要的效果
is I want to really make sure
是把这些图片都
these images are square.
调成正方形
Now they may look square to you
也许大家看起来觉得已经很方了
but they really aren't, and I'll
但其实真的不是  我可以证明给
prove it to you.
大家看
I'm going to control drag from
我现在按住控制键  拖拽
the image to itself and select
图片到自身上  然后选择
the aspect ratio constraint.
宽高比约束
And you can see when I pop this
等这个窗口弹出来
open it actually says a
就能看到  图片
multiplier of 193 to 226.
其实是 193 乘 226 的
Let's go ahead and make it 1:1.
我们现在就把这个比例设成一比一
Okay. But something didn't quite
好了  但似乎画布上什么反应都
happen there.
没有
Nothing happened in canvas and,
画布上什么变化都没有
in fact, my aspect ratio is red.
而且我的宽高比还变红了
And what's worse, if you take a
更糟糕的是  如果我们看
look over here, there's a little
一下这里  还出现了一个
red dot.
小红点
And so, when we click on that,
我们点击一下这个小红点
we have a whole bunch of
可以看到这里有好多
conflicting constraints.
冲突的约束条件
What happened?
发生了什么
Well, let's go ahead and debug
我们一起回溯  排查一下哪里
this together.
出错了
And I'll give you -- we'll show
我会给  我会向大家
you a technique for how to
展示一个如何着手解决
approach this type of problem
画布上这种报错问题的
within the canvas.
小技巧
So I've got the aspect ratio and
这里我们设置了宽高比
I want to, first of all,
首先我希望
validate that this is the thing
能够确认  到底是不是
that introduced error.
宽高比导致了报错
Some I'm going to go to the
所以我现在就去
attribute inspector for the
约束的属性审查器
constraint and then toggle the
找到安装按钮  然后
installed button on and off to
在打开和关闭两者间切换一下
see what happens.
看看会怎样
And so, when I toggle it off, my
好了  我切换到关闭  这些
issues disappear.
报错就消失了
And when I toggle it on, they
切换到打开时  它们
appear again.
又出现了
But nothing's really happening
但画布上还是没有任何
in the canvas, so the next
变化  所以我要
strategy I'd like to do is I
尝试的下一个策略
like to poke around in my
就是去布局里面找找
layout.
问题
And the thing I care about is
我可能需要关心的
probably the other red
问题  是周围这些
constraints that are nearby.
其他的被标红的约束
Let's go ahead and take a look
我们先从这一个由堆栈
at the one from the outermost
最外层视图到顶端的
stack view to the top.
约束着手
And when we uninstall that, the
如果我们卸载这个约束
issues disappear but we're no
报错消失了  但子视图就
longer fitting in the superview.
无法平分铺满父视图了
But the images are nice and
不过图片倒是都变成了
square.
正方形
That's kind of an interesting
这个效果挺有意思的
effect.
我们再去试试其他的
one.
比如我现在卸载一下这个
And I'm going uninstall the
然后再卸载一下
trailing constraint.
右侧约束
And you can see again we're
可以看到  和刚刚一样
square but this time we're
图片变正方形了  但这次
overflowing our superview.
显示也超出了父视图
And so what's actually happening
所以这里的问题其实是
is that we can't satisfy both
我们无法同时满足
the aspect ratio constraint, the
宽高比约束
fill equally distribution on the
和在堆栈视图上沿垂直线
stack views, and then have it
平分的约束  然后还要让它们
fit into the superview.
能装进父视图里
Luckily, for my case, I don't
但幸运的是  这个例子里
need to fill the entire
我不需要铺满整个
superview.
父视图
What I really want is actually
我其实只希望图片
to just stick to the top.
能够置顶显示
So if I uninstall this, this is
所以我只需卸载这个约束
closer to what I want.
这样就差不多了
But supposing we rotate in a
但假设我们要旋转屏幕
landscape and my height gets
横屏显示时  显示高度会
smaller, I still want this
变小  而如果我还保留
constraint so [inaudible] that
这个约束  那么还是会超出父视图
And so what I'm going to do is
所以我现在要做的就是
I'm going to leave it installed
先不卸载这个约束
and set it to greater than or
而是把它设置成大于或
equal to, and then this is more
等于  这差不多就是
of what I want in portrait.
我想要的竖屏效果了
Let's go ahead back to the
我们现在再回到
object outline and we're now
对象大纲  现在我们要考虑
going to look at landscape.
的是横屏显示的布局
When I click the device bar on
我现在在设备栏里点击一下
landscape, you can see there's
横屏  可以看到我们还有
some work that we have to do
一些调整工作需要做
here.
首先要做的一点
we want to get closer to the
我们希望能更接近
look that we were wanting.
我们之前设想的布局
And, if you remember, the top
如果大家还记得  这个
[inaudible] label needs to
Top Dates 的文本标签得
disappear, and then we're going
弄没  然后还需要
to eventually put a text view
在右侧空出一块地方放一个
over on the right.
文本视图
So let's first work on the top
我们先来看一下怎么处理
[inaudible] label.
这个文本标签
I'm going to click on it and a
点击一下这个标签
stack view -- the thing we could
堆栈视图里  有一个我们
do is we could use the hidden
可以用的属性  隐藏
property.
属性
Stack view is really great with
堆栈视图里很适合使用
hidden subviews because it will
隐藏的子视图  因为堆栈视图
also collapse their layout but
可以在布局时自动收起子视图
keep them in the arranged
但还会将它们保留在
subviews array.
子视图组里
Now, we'll go over to hidden
我们找到隐藏属性
property, and actually new to
Xcode 9 还提供了一项新功能
Xcode 9, we also allow you to
我们还可以根据不同屏幕
vary this by size class.
尺寸方向 (Size Class)  选择显示或隐藏
And so you can see --
在这里可以看到
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
There's a plus button to make
这里有个展开按钮  更方便
that easier.
设置
And so I'm going to pop it up
点击打开这个窗口
and choose any width.
选择任何宽度
And in this case, because it's
针对我们的情况  因为
landscape, it is compact type.
是横屏  选择紧凑型 (Compact)
You could also verify that with
也可以通过底部的
the device bar on the bottom.
设备栏再次进行确认
Right now we're in landscape
我们现在设置的是横屏的
iPhone seven plus with regular
iPhone 7+  普通型
width and compact type.
宽度  和紧凑型高度
So for any width compact type,
现在  选好任何宽度加紧凑型高度
I'm going to add a variation,
我来添加一个差异项
mark it as hidden, and there we
并标记为隐藏  好了
And, if we switch over to
现在我们再返回
portrait, it appears.
竖屏  标签又出现了
Going back to landscape, it's
回到横屏状态
disappeared.
又消失了
Okay. We need to add our text
好了  现在就剩下添加文本
view now.
视图了
And, in order to do that, we
为了添加这个视图
need a outer horizontal view.
我们需要在外面包一个水平视图
We need some sort of horizontal
得添加一个水平的
stack view for being able to
堆栈视图  才能装载
host the text view.
一个文本视图
So I'm going to select
所以我现在选中
everything here.
全部这些
And then I'm going to type text
然后在对象大纲里
view in the object outline
打一下 text view
because I want to add that in.
好添加到画布上
Let's go ahead and embed the
我们现在就用插入
outer view using the embed and
堆栈视图按钮添加一个
stack button.
外围视图
So it created a new stack view,
这就新建了一个堆栈视图
and we need to switch it over to
我们还得把这个视图切换到
be -- that's vertical.
这个视图是垂直的
We need to switch it over to be
我们得把它切换成
horizontal.
水平的
Everything shrunk down because
所有元素都缩小了
also, since I embedded it into
是因为我把东西都插入到
new view, it got rid of my
新视图中了  所以就取消了
constraints to the superview.
它们和父视图相关的所有约束
So we need to make it
我们把这个调成
horizontal.
水平的
Let's go ahead and give it a
把我们刚刚新建的
standard spacing for the
那个外围视图设置
outermost one we just created.
成标准间距
And then we can add a new text
然后就可以添加这个新的文本
view.
视图了
So we'll just go ahead and drag
让我们把这个拖拽进来
that in.
添加
There it is.
好了
And then we need to rebuild the
然后还需要重新约束一下
constraints to our superview for
外围这个视图  把它约束到
the outermost one.
父视图上
So I'm going to go back to the
我们再回到
pinning menu 10, 10, 10, 10.
固定菜单  设置  10，10，10，10
And then the bottommost
还有一个最底端的
constraint, if you remember --
约束  如果大家还记得
I'll zoom in here -- is going to
我把这里放大一下  设置成
be greater than or equal to.
大于或等于
Okay. And so this is what I want
好了  这就是我想要的横屏
for landscape.
效果了
When we switch back to portrait,
现在我们切换回竖屏
we actually have to do a similar
再重复一下类似的过程
thing and hide the text view by
让这个文本视图根据屏幕尺寸大小
a size class.
隐藏
And so we can click on this.
点击一下文本视图
Go over to the hidden menu again
再找出隐藏菜单
and add a variation --
添加一个差异项
Of any width, regular height,
设置任何宽度  普通型高度
and then mark it as hidden.
然后标记为隐藏
And now we have the look that we
现在就达成了我们最终想要的效果
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So use the stack view, when you
总结一下  对于我们所有的布局
can, for all your layouts.
能用堆栈视图就用
Alignment, distribution,
对齐方式  子视图分布
spacing.
子视图间距
Those are properties that will
这几项属性非常
get you there, including
有用  还包括
nesting.
嵌套
Add just a few constraints.
只需添加少数几条约束
We only noticed it needed aspect
唯一需要注意的是  要按比例
ratio constraint to get the
布置  需要添加宽高比
proportion.
约束
So you only need a few
所以如果有  比如
constraints to get you a little
按比例布局的需求  其实只
bit extra if you have some
需要手动添加很少几个约束
requirements like the
就可以达到所需的额外
proportion.
效果
The hidden property in Xcode 9
Xcode 9 里的隐藏属性可以根据
is size classable, which is
屏幕大小尺寸设置开关  非常
great.
方便
You can go ahead and use it, and
大家都可以去尝试一下
it works great with stack view,
尤其和堆栈视图配合使用  效果杰出
because stack view will collapse
因为堆栈视图会自动收起
hidden subviews.
隐藏的子视图
And best of all, varying by size
而最好的一点是  根据屏幕尺寸大小
class with the hidden property
隐藏的属性  可自动应用在
is backwards deployable.
所有旧版代码上
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, in summary, we've looked at
总结一下  我们今天一共展示了
six techniques today, and this
六项内容  大家学会
is going to add to your arsenal
这六项新技术  就可以更好地
for being able to build out your
完善各位在开发的应用
apps.
程序
We cannot wait to see what you
我们非常期盼着能看到各位的应用成果
And today we looked at some
我们今天看到了一些
techniques for being able to do
技术  可以帮助我们在
dynamic layout within the
运行时进行动态布局
Things like dynamic type, as
比方说  动态字体
well as layout techniques, for
还看到了布局技术
being able to handle and make
可以帮助我们调整内容显示
your content look great,
呈现更棒的显示效果
unobscured, and handle adaptive
让内容不受遮挡  还可以进行自适应
layout.
布局
For more information, you could
更多详细信息  大家可以
check out the
去这个网址查看
developerapple.com.
developerapple.com
If you want to learn more about
如果大家对动态字体感兴趣
dynamic type, you could check
想了解更多相关信息  也可以
out the session this afternoon
去听一下今天下午的那场演讲
and there are also links to past
这里还有一些往期相关演讲的
videos.
链接
Have a wonderful WWDC, everyone.
祝大家在 WWDC 过得愉快